export const data = [
  {
    id: 1,
    class: "8th",
    topic: "Sound",
    duration: "10 mins",
    questionsList: [
      {
        "questionText": "Sound is caused by _________ of an object.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "movement",
          "wavelenght",
          "vibrations",
          "frequency"
        ],
        "answer": "vibrations",
        "solution": "Sound is caused by vibrations of an object."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "When air has been removed completely from a vessel, it is said that there is a ________ in the vessel.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "vacuum",
          "air",
          "water",
          "atmosphere"
        ],
        "answer": "vacuum",
        "solution": "When air has been removed completely from a vessel, it is said that there is a vacuum in the vessel."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "Frequency is expressed in ________ . Its symbol is ______.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "secound, sec",
          "kilometer, pa ",
          "meter, Hz",
          "hertz, Hz"
        ],
        "answer": "hertz, Hz",
        "solution": "Frequency is expressed in hertz. Its symbol is Hz."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "The frequency determines the ________ of a sound.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "shrillness or pitch",
          "frequency",
          "amplitude",
          "meter"
        ],
        "answer": "shrillness or pitch",
        "solution": "The frequency determines the ________ of a sound. "
      },
      {
        "questionText": "for human ear, the range of audible frequencies is roughly from _______________ .",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "200 to 20,000 Hz",
          "10 to 20,000 Hz",
          "20 to 20,000 Hz",
          "20 to 10,000 Hz"
        ],
        "answer": "20 to 20,000 Hz",
        "solution": "The number of oscillations per second is called the frequency of oscillation. Frequency is expressed in hertz. Its symbol is Hz. "
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    class: "8th",
    topic: "Light",
    duration: "10 mins",
    questionsList: [
      {
        "questionText": "  First the laws of reflection is angle of _________ is always equal to the angle of __________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "incidence, reflection",
          "incident, reflected ray",
          "incident, normal",
          "normal, reflection"
        ],
        "answer": "incidence, reflection",
        "solution": "angle of incidence is always equal to the angle of reflection(<i=<r)."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "2nd Law of reflection is the incident ray, the normal ________________ and the reflected ray all lie in the same plane..",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "in the point of incidence",
          "on the point of incidence",
          "at the point of incidence",
          "upon the point of incidence"
        ],
        "answer": "at the point of incidence",
        "solution": " 2nd Law of reflection is,the incident ray, the normal at the point of incidence and the reflected ray all lie in the same plane."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "An image formed by a plane mirror the left of the object appears on the right and the right appears on the left. This is known as ______________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "regular reflection",
          "diffused reflection",
          "inversion",
          "lateral inversion"
        ],
        "answer": "lateral inversion",
        "solution": "An image formed by a plane mirror the left of the object appears on the right and the right appears on the left. This is known as lateral inversion."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "Splitting of light into its colours is known as ___________ of light.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "reflection",
          "dispersion",
          "diffusion",
          "VIBGYOR"
        ],
        "answer": "dispersion",
        "solution": "Splitting of light into its colours is known as dispersion of light."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "__________, which are sensitive to bright light.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "cornea",
          "iris",
          "cones",
          "rods"
        ],
        "answer": "cones",
        "solution": "Cones, which are sensitive to bright light. "
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    class: "8th",
    topic: "Chemical Effects of Electricity",
    duration: "10 mins",
    questionsList: [
      {
        "questionText": " The process of depositing a layer of any desired metal on another material by means of electricity is called________________ .",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "electroplating",
          "chemical plating",
          "galvanization",
          "electrods",
        ],
        "answer": "electroplating",
        "solution": "The process of depositing a layer of any desired metal on another material by means of electricity is called electroplating."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "When electric current is passed through the copper sulphate solution, copper sulphate dissociates into ________________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "copper and sulpher",
          "copper and sulphate",
          "zinc and sulphate",
          "zinc and copper",
        ],
        "answer": "copper and sulphate",
        "solution": " When electric current is passed through the copper sulphate solution, copper sulphate dissociates into copper and sulphate."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "A coating of zinc is deposited on iron to protect it from corrosion and formation of rust is called  ______________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "electroplating",
          "chemical plating ",
          "galvanization",
          "electrods",
        ],
        "answer": "galvanization",
        "solution": "A coating of zinc is deposited on iron to protect it from corrosion and formation of rust is called galvanization."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " distilled water is a _____________ .",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "neutral",
          "super conductor",
          "good conductor",
          "bad conductor"
        ],
        "answer": "bad conductor",
        "solution": "distilled water is a bad conductor."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "In electroplating the free copper gets drawn to the electrode connected to the ______________of the battery and gets deposited on it.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "blue terminal",
          "neutral terminal",
          "negative terminal",
          "positive terminal"
        ],
        "answer": "negative terminal",
        "solution": "In electroplating the free copper gets drawn to the electrode connected to the negative terminal of the battery and gets deposited on it. "
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    class: "7th",
    topic: "Forests: Our Lifeline",
    duration: "10 mins",
    questionsList: [
      {
        "questionText": "The branches of the tall trees look like a roof over the other plants in the forest is called  __________________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "canopy",
          "emergent layer",
          "understory",
          "forest floor",
        ],
        "answer": "canopy",
        "solution": "The branches of the tall trees look like a roof over the other plants in the forest is called canopy."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "The micro-organisms which convert the dead plants and animals to humus are known as _______________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "humus",
          "decomposers",
          "black colour substance",
          "red soil",
        ],
        "answer": "decomposers",
        "solution": "The micro-organisms which convert the dead plants and animals to humus are known as decomposers."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " If forests disappear, the amount of carbon dioxide in air will _____________, resulting in the increase of earth’s temperature .",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "decrease",
          "reduce",
          "increase",
          "remain same",
        ],
        "answer": "increase",
        "solution": "If forests disappear, the amount of carbon dioxide in air will increase, resulting in the increase of earth’s temperature."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " Forests protect the soil from _______________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "none of there",
          "reducing",
          "distruction",
          "erosion",
        ],
        "answer": "erosion ",
        "solution": "Forests protect the soil from erosion. ",
      },
      {
        "questionText": "​The organisms that feed on the dead and decaying organisms are called ________________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "trophs",
          "saphrotrophs",
          "autotrophs",
          "heterotrophs",
        ],
        "answer": "saphrotrophs",
        "solution": "The organisms that feed on the dead and decaying organisms are called saprotrophs. ",
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    class: "7th",
    topic: "Light",
    duration: "10 mins",
    questionsList: [
      {
        "questionText": "A mirror changes the direction of light that falls on it. This change of direction by a mirror is called ____________________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "electric fuses",
          "reflection",
          "reflection of light",
          "refraction of light",
        ],
        "answer": "reflection of light",
        "solution": "A mirror changes the direction of light that falls on it. This change of direction by a mirror is called reflection of light."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " the image formed by a plane mirror could not be obtained on a screen. Such an image is called a __________________ .",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "plain image",
          "virtual",
          "virtual image",
          "real image",
        ],
        "answer": "virtual image",
        "solution": "the image formed by a plane mirror could not be obtained on a screen. Such an image is called a virtual image."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " A ____________ splits a beam of sunlight into ______________colours.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "iron and seven",
          "magnet and seven",
          "seven and prism",
          "prism and seven",
        ],
        "answer": "prism and seven",
        "solution": "A prism splits a beam of sunlight into seven colours."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " the image formed by a plane mirror could not be obtained on a screen. Such an image is called a _______________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "false image",
          "real image",
          "vertual image",
          "virtual image",
        ],
        "answer": "virtual image",
        "solution": "the image formed by a plane mirror could not be obtained on a screen. Such an image is called a virtual image. ",
      },
      {
        "questionText": "Image formed by a convex mirror is ____________, _______________ and smaller in size than the object.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "heating and cooling",
          "erect, virtual",
          "erect, real",
          "magnet and real",
        ],
        "answer": "erect, virtual",
        "solution": "Image formed by a convex mirror is erect, virtual and smaller in size than the object.",
      },
    ]
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    class: "7th",
    topic: "Chemical effects of electicity",
    duration: "10 mins",
    questionsList: [
      {
        "questionText": "Wires made from some special materials melt quickly and break when large electric currents are passed through them. These wires are used for making _____________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "electric fuse",
          "circuit",
          "switch",
          "wire",
        ],
        "answer": "electric fuse",
        "solution": "Wires made from some special materials melt quickly and break when large electric currents are passed through them. These wires are used for making electric fuse."
      },
      {
        "questionText": "When an electric current flows through a wire, it behaves like a _____________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "electric wire",
          "magnet",
          "circuit",
          "iron rod ",
        ],
        "answer": "magnet",
        "solution": "When an electric current flows through a wire, it behaves like a magnet."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " A current carrying coil of an insulated wire wrapped around a piece of iron is called an ____________________ .",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "electric wire",
          "magent",
          "electromagnet",
          "switch",
        ],
        "answer": "electromagnet",
        "solution": "A current carrying coil of an insulated wire wrapped around a piece of iron is called an electromagnet."
      },
      {
        "questionText": " the image formed by a plane mirror could not be obtained on a screen. Such an image is called a _______________.",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "false image",
          "real image",
          "vertual image",
          "virtual image",
        ],
        "answer": "virtual image",
        "solution": "the image formed by a plane mirror could not be obtained on a screen. Such an image is called a virtual image. ",
      },
      {
        "questionText": "When an electric current flows through a wire, the wire gets heated. It is the ______________ current",
        "questionImage": "",
        "options": [
          "heating",
          "boiling effect of",
          "melting effect of",
          "heating effect of",
        ],
        "answer": "heating effect of",
        "solution": "When an electric current flows through a wire, the wire gets heated. It is the heating effect of current ",
      },
    ]
  }
]